Sharon P. Mulzac, MS, RD, CDN.

908-986-7303

smulzacrd@gmail.com

SUMMARY: Multi-dimensional Registered Dietitian /Nutritionist with Master's degree and 20 years of experience in the field of Dietetics seeking a Public Health Consultant 2 Nutrition position within the Department of Health. I am highly customer focused, do medical nutrition therapy and counselling, curriculum development and teaching as well as culinary demonstration. I am an excellent team leader and staff motivator. I am passionate about helping people to eat healthy and live better and more empowered lives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Clinical Nutritionist/Dietitian, NJ State Department of Human Services 2020 - Present

- Provide ongoing clinical nutrition care to all clients at Glenbrook Regional Center
- Maintain documentation of all phases in the clinical nutrition care process
- Participate in treatment team meetings of all clients
- Collaborate with physicians and other members of the clinical team to ensue treatment plan goals are implemented
- Communicate & collaborate with the Food service department for best quality outcomes
- Provide in service training to all departments

Consulting Dietitian & Dietitian in Private Practice

2018 - Present

- Group and Individual Counselling
- Lunch and Learn
- Nutrition counselling to minority/Community groups as it relates to improving their overall Nutritional health status and preventing/managing chronic diseases
- Generate and Analyze Monthly Cycle Menu in keeping with NY State Standards
- Consult with corporate & food production staff for quality outcomes as necessary corporate/production staff as needed

Clinical Dietitian HCR- Manor Care

2015-2020

- Provide nutritional screening and assessment of residents in sub-acute and long-term care setting, ensuring their diet well-being and satisfaction
- Quality Assurance collection, analysis and reporting
- Consult with Medical, Administrative and clinical staff concerning residents 'nutrition plan of care
- Acting Food Service Director in his absence
- Serve as the nutrition services liaison between families and the facility

Clinical Dietician Cobble Hill Health Center

2009 - 2015

 Do nutritional screening and assessment of residents in sub-acute and long-term care setting

- Coordinate with the food-service managers for improved residents' meal satisfaction
- Consult with Administrative and Clinical staff regarding residents' care plan
- Provide nutrition education, counseling and reinforcement to residents and family members
- Quality Assurance collection, analysis and reporting

Food-Service Supervisor/ Dietitian Brooklyn Center for Rehabilitation

2003 - 2009

- Direct the nutritional area of the Food-service Department
- Coordinate with the Food-service Manager to set goals for the department
- Participate in setting sanitation standards for the department
- Provide in-service training to food-service staff and other departments
- Menu preparation, revision, analysis and implementation
- Place food orders in the absence of the Food-Service Manager, ensuring proper budget
- Quality Assurance collection, analysis and reporting
- Nutritional assessment and care planning for residents
- Consult with Administrative and clinical staff concerning residents' care
- Development and implementation of Department Policies and Procedures
- Precept Dietetic Interns

Community Dietitian, Community Healthcare Network

2000 - 2004

- Assess nutritional status of patients for all life cycles
- Provide medical nutritional therapy to patients and their families
- Meal planning and modification to meet nutrition prescription
- Nutrition education, counseling and reinforcement to patients with different medical condition including dyslipidemia, diabetes, hypertension, HIV/AIDS, obesity and GI problems.
- Provide education to home health aides on basic principles of nutrition, shopping and food safety
- Act as the liaison between clients and community services including the WIC program

EDUCATION

1999- 2005 Master of Science in Clinical Nutrition, Brooklyn College, CUNY

1993-1998 Bachelor of Science, Nutrition, Brooklyn College, CUNY

2007- 2008 Dietetic Internship- Brooklyn College, CUNY

1985-1987 Teacher Certification in Primary education, St. Vincent Teacher's College

Professional Affiliations & Credentials

- Registered Dietitian Nutritionist(RDN): The Commission on Dietetic Registration
- Certified Dietitian-Nutritionist: New York State Dietetic Association
- Certificate in Adult Weight Management
- Board member: Association for Healthcare Foodservice NJ and National Chapters(AHF-NJ)
- Member of the American Diabetes Association

Career Achievements/Volunteer Work:

• Contributed to compliance with federal and state regulations by establishing policies, procedures and quality assurance management programs for Food-Service Department.

- Trained and monitored all production staff to practice food safety standards that resulted in improved operating procedures
- Planned and coordinated the Dietetic Internship Program for students from Brooklyn College, including mentoring and supervision of students annually for their food-service and clinical rotations
- Evaluated and recommended the restructuring of the diet office and production workflow to improve efficiency and productivity without cutting patient/customer service and care.